cityofpasadena.net 2005-02-06

# City of Pasadena Privacy Policy

|   tsunami relief  
---  
state of the city 2005  
election info  
rose bowl renovation  
flu information  
parking pay station program  
 general plan  
 city hall project  
la loma bridge  
710 mitigation   
gold line/ ARTS   
lookin' good pasadena  
emergency preparedness   
arroyo seco  
  
The City of Pasadena recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of the visitors to this Web site and views this site as a tool for providing City-wide information and interactive services to its citizens. We collect no personal information about you when you visit our site unless you choose to provide that information to us.  We do not give, share, sell, or transfer any personal information to a third party. 

Should you provide the City of Pasadena with personal information such as sending an e-mail or by filling out and submitting an online form located on the City of Pasadena's Web site, the information may be used to respond to you and to assist in providing you with the information or service requested. The City of Pasadena treats e-mail messages and submitted online forms the same way it treats letters to City officials.

The City of Pasadena does not create individual profiles with the information provided by users of this site, nor does it give such personal information to third parties or private organizations. The City of Pasadena does not collect information for commercial marketing from its Web site. We will not send you unsolicited email regarding any commercial offers or advertisements at any time. 

The City of Pasadena’s Web site contains links to external sites. The City of Pasadena is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of these sites. 

The City of Pasadena does analyze user traffic patterns on our website from information automatically provided by your browser when you visit our site. This information is used to gather statistics about visitors as a whole and in no way points to individuals. This information includes:

1\. The Internet domain name (for example, “xcompany.com” if you use a private Internet access account or “yourschool.edu” if you connect from a university’s domain)  
2\. The IP address from which you access the City’s website  
3\. The date, time and pages you visited on our site  
4\. Your browser and operating system  
5\. The referring page (the last web page you visited before clicking on a link to our site)

In order to provide electronic commerce capabilities, the name, address and payment information (if applicable) that you provide may be collected and processed to complete an online transaction and for record-keeping activities such as billing, licenses and other business-related purposes.

The City of Pasadena monitors network traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to access, change or destroy information. Anyone using this website expressly consents to such monitoring.

Notwithstanding the provisions listed previously in this section, information submitted to the City of Pasadena's site may be subject to disclosure to another party pursuant to various provisions of California law, including, but not limited to, the California Civil Discovery Act of 1986 and the California Public Records Act. The City of Pasadena only shares such information with another government agency if the inquiry relates to that agency, to protect the interests of others, to protect and defend the rights or property of the City of Pasadena or as otherwise required by applicable state and federal laws.

The City of Pasadena is required by the Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act of 1996 (HIPAA) to maintain the privacy of certain confidential health care information, known as “Protected Health Information,” or “PHI,” and to provide you with a notice of the City’s legal duties and privacy practices regarding your PHI. This Notice describes your legal rights, advises you of the City’s privacy practices, and explains the circumstances under which the City is permitted to use and disclose PHI about you.     
The HIPAA notice can be downloaded from the following links:

HIPAA notice (English)  
HIPAA notice (Spanish)  

|
